ENG SHI LE

LANGUAGES

English

Proficient

••••

SKILLS

Language

JavaScript •TypeScript •Phyton•PHP

Front End

HTML • CSS • SASS • Bootstrap •
Tailwind • MUI • Styled-components
• React • Redux • Next.js • React
Hooks • React Context • Redux
Persist • React Query • React Table

Back End

Node.js • Express • Django • NestJS • Laravel • GraphQL • RESTful API • tRPC • Flask • Java C#

UI Design

UX/UI • Figma • Sketch • Zeplin

Database

MongoDB • MySQL • PostgreSQL • Sqlite • Supabase • Firebase • HBase • Airtable

Testing Approach & Frameworks

TDD • Jest • ESlint • Cypress • PHPUnit • PyTest

Cloud Framework / Technologies

Docker • AWS •

Google Cloud Platform • Azure

React Full Stack Developer

(1)+65 82002515

@alberteng0825@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/eng-shi-le-b7b2212a4

Block 461, Choa Chu Kang Ave 4, #08-75, Choa Chu Kang New Town, Northwest, Singapore 680461.

SUMMARY

I am an experienced full-stack web developer with over 5 years of experience handling all aspects of the development process for high-scale web and mobile applications. My proficiency in diverse industries such as Blockchain, E-commerce, Healthcare, and Education has allowed me to understand my clients' business needs successfully. I have built and managed secure websites and possess comprehensive knowledge of web security.

My expertise includes working with Linux command line tools, and I pride myself on writing clean, well-tested, and well-documented code.

In addition to this, I have successfully completed projects with tight deadlines in high-stress environments. As a result, I am resourceful, self-motivated, and proactive in ensuring project success.

With a pragmatic approach, I handle the front-end to back-end tasks, including hosting, site design, and system administration.

I do not shy away from responsibilities and never use phrases like "That's not my job." Throughout my career, I have collaborated with multi-functional teams and have been successful in delivering 40= projects.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Informatics Engineering

2014 - 2018

Central Carolina Technical College

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Developer

04/2023 - Present

Upwork

Location

- Handled several text and image processing tasks based on Python and Django
- Managed tens of clients living in different timezones
- Provided clear updates and keeping the tight deadlines
- Provided 100% work success rate
- · Developed several Solana game projects such as roulette and spin wheels

React Front End Developer (Remote, Contract)

10/2022 - 04/2023

Mad Dog Car Club

LICA

- Developed the front end of 3 projects using React, SASS, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Material-UI, TypeScript, Next.js, React Hooks, Context API, and Styled-components
- Integrated web3 parts into Ethereum, Solana and Cardano projects using web3.js and ethers.js
- Resolved image optimization and utilized a cookie parser to improve the performance of page loading by 240%
- Transformed the user experience by incorporating lazy loading via a streamlined and effective paginated API.
- Resulted in a 60% improvement in page loading speed and substantial decrease in bounce rates
- Collaborated closely with the designer and backend developer, maintaining good teamwork through communication channels such as Slack, Trello, and weekly scrum meetings

SKILLS

Hosting & Domain service

cPanel • Namecheap • Ionos • Vercel • Netlify • Heroku • Railway • Hostinger

ΑI

OpenAI • Dalle Model • Tensorflow • Deep Learning • Keras • Whisper

Project Management Tool

Jira • Trello • Asana • Zoho • Clickup

EXPERIENCE

React Full Stack Developer (Remote, Contract)

03/2022 - 10/2022

AutoScribe

AWS for 2 months

USA Oversaw the entire development process from start to finish using React, Django,

- Crafted and executed an MFA user authentication system that uplifted security by 50%, flawlessly integrated payment processing, resulting in a revenue jump of 30%, and pioneered AI audio processing
- 2 Mobile app development using React Native, Expo UI, Laravel, Node.js, Firebase, Supabase
- To ensure scalability, used a cloud-based hosting solution and implemented load balancing to distribute traffic across multiple servers.
- Optimized the website's performance by implementing caching, minimizing page load times, and optimizing images and other media files
- Revamped website traffic and user experience by 37%

Full Stack Blockchain Engineer (Remote, Full-time)

03/2020 - 03/2022

Taiwan

Bitfinex

Created and optimized components using React and Next.js. Cut development speed by 9%

- Drove best practice implementation for 22 employees across multiple departments. Decreased rework by 23% and costs by 15%
- Introduced effective database caching schema. Improved database access rate by 17%
- Structured REST-based web services and serverless backend. Increased the user interaction by 30%
- Enhanced the Software Quality 15% by fixing the 150 bugs using React, Next.js, Express, Django, Laravel, AWS, Docker, Java, .NET
- Developed and launched 2 DeFi projects using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, Web3.js and Smart contracts

Full Stack Developer (Hybrid Remote, Full-Time)

12/2018 - 02/2020

Resonac Hard Disk Singapore Pte Ltd

SG

- Played a key role in the development, improvement, and operation of 7 web-based software using React
- Gained hands-on expertise in Node, Express, Nest, Django and other back-end frameworks as well as front-end frameworks and library such as React and Next.js
- Involved in new mock-ups and UI specifications for holiday events and raised 25% more in total sale leads
- Upgraded an ecommerce web apps to sell products online using Laravel and Wordpress. Expanded company revenue by 58%